没搞错吧
Are you kidding me?
乔伊
Joey?
乔伊  乔伊  乔伊  乔伊...
Joey? Joey, Joey, Joey, Joey, Joey, Joey, Joey!
乔伊  乔伊  乔伊
Joey. Joey. Joey.
乔伊  乔伊
Joey, Joey!
耶
Yeah.
喔   我吵醒你了
Oh. Oh, did-did-did I wake you?
老友记  第四季  第20集  婚纱
Friends  S04E20  The One With All the Wedding Dresses
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
（中央咖啡馆）
阿甘  再给我添一杯咖啡  好吗
Gunther, could I get another cup of coffee? please?
那个  你不工作时都干些什么啊
So, uh, what do you do when you're not working here?
你用不着没话找话   好  谢了
You don't need to fill these silences. Okay, thanks.
钱德   这是你喝得第四杯了
Chandler, that's your fourth cup of coffee.
我喝这么多还不是因为我太累了  因为乔伊开始打呼了
Well, I am drinking lots of cups of coffee because I'm exhausted because Joey started snoring.
他睡在隔壁  有那么大声吗
He's in a different room. He's really that loud?
你都该过来听听
Oh, you should hear me.
你还得意  你应该去睡眠诊所看看
It's not something to be proud of. okay? You have to go to a sleep clinic!
我说过  我不去做任何诊疗
Look, I told you, I'm not going to any clinic.
我没问题  是你有问题
I don't have a problem. You're the one with the problem.
你该去 "少任性别管我" 诊所
You should go to a "Quit-beinga-baby-and-leave-me-alone" clinic.
没有那种诊所  当然有了
They don't have those. Yeah, they do.
"少任性别管我"
Quit being a baby and leave me alone!
看么  你刚上了第一课
There, you just had your first class.
我曾跟一个男的约会  他的睡眠很浅
I used to go out with this guy that was a light sleeper.
只要我一打呼噜  他就把我翻过来
And whenever I'd snore, he'd roll me over...
啊哦  喔
Oh, yeah.
他把我翻过来  我就不打呼噜了
He'd roll me over, and I'd stop snoring.
下次你再打  我就把你翻过去
Next time you snore, I'm rolling you over!
我忙我的  你玩你的
I gotta do what I gotta do. You gotta do what you gotta do.
嘿  兄弟  嘿
Hey, guys. Hey.
奥运主题曲
Oh, the Olympics!
大喜之日定了吗
Have you guys picked a date yet?
还没有
No. Not yet.
我还是不能相信你订婚了
I still can not believe you're engaged.
因为事情来得太快了  不是因为你是个失败者
Just 'cause its happening so fast; not 'cause you're such a loser.
谢谢  有人看到瑞秋了吗
Thanks. Uh, has anyone seen Rach?
她在楼上  没在洗盘子
Mm, she's upstairs not doing the dishes.
我告诉你  这次我绝不妥协
And I'll tell you, I'm not doing them this time.
我才不在乎碗盘堆到有多高了
I don't care if those dishes sit until they're covered...
我回家就洗
I'll do them when I get home.
对了
Yeah. Oh, hey.
艾蜜莉在伦敦看中一件婚纱
Um, Emily found this wedding dress in London...
这么快  对  但尺寸不合适
Already? Yeah, but it didn't fit.
幸运是  这里有家店有合适的
Luckily, there's a store here with one left in her size.
但我是新郎  不能看见礼服
But I'm the groom, I'm not supposed to see the dress…
我去帮你拿  谢谢
I'll pick it up for you. Thank you.
她让你跑腿  帮她拿婚纱
She's got you running errands, picking up wedding dresses...
哗啪
Ha-ha-ha. Wah-pah!
什么是 "哗啪"
What's "wah-pah"?
你知道  鞭打啊
You know. Whipped.
哗啪
Wah-pah!
那才不是鞭打  鞭打是wh-tcssh
That's not whipped. Whipped is wh-tcssh!
没错啊
That's what I did.
哗啪
Wah-pah!
你什么都不会
You can't do anything!
摩妮卡
Hey, Mon.
我正在洗碗  嘿
I was just doing these dishes. Oh... Hey.
嗯  你有空吗
Hi. Do you, uh, have a minute?
有  反正我正打算休息
Yeah, I was just about to take a break anyway.
是这样的  嗯
So listen, uh...
艾蜜莉和我决定结婚以后
...I know you and I haven't had a chance to talk...
我们还没有机会谈谈
...since, uh, Emily and I decided to get married.
我想知道你还好吧
And I was just wondering how you were.
还行啦
Ahem. Oh.
如果是你要结婚  我会觉得有点
If you were getting married, heh, I would feel kind of...
你懂吗   懂
You know? Yeah, yeah.
我的确吓了一跳  不过
It def... Uh, it definitely took me by surprise. But, you know...
我没事
...uh, I'm okay.
真的  对
Yeah? Yeah.
我就是想问下
I just wanted to check.
你真好  谢谢
Oh, that's sweet. Thank you. Oh, ha, ha.
你真好
You're great. Hmm.
我知道你也总会有这一天的
And I know someday this will happen for you too.
撑着点
You just hang in there. Ahem.
"撑着点"
"Hang in there"?
不  我不是说
Oh, no, I didn't mean...
你大概还没听说过一场真恋情  叫 "我与约书亚"吗
I mean maybe you didn't hear about a serious relationship called "me and Joshua"?
我以为你们就约会过四次
Oh, I thought you guys had just been on like four dates,
没想到已经有进展了
I didn't realize that had become anything.
是的  已经是有了进展
Oh, yeah. Oh, no, it has become.
可不是  四次美妙的约会
Yeah. Oh, no, those were four great dates.
是啊  是
Oh. Yeah? Oh, yeah.
我们很默契  你知道
I mean, and the connection! I mean, you know.
感情上的  心灵上的
Emotionally, mentally. You know?
身体上的
Physically.
太好了  真是难以置信  可不是吗
Wow. That's incredible. I know, isn't it?
我跟约书亚在一起那么合拍   你跟艾蜜莉在一起也是
I'm right there with Joshua. You are right there with Emily.
有点像  大家打个平手
And it's y'know, it's kind of like it's a tie.
我得继续洗碗了
Well, I gotta get, I gotta get back to the dishes.
我得回去上班了  好的
I gotta get to work. Oh, yeah.
你知道做什么会让我很开心吗
Hey, y'know, y'know make me really happy?
是吗  做什么
Oh, yeah, no, what's that?
就是如果我们四个能在一起聚一聚
If like the four of us could all y'know, hang out together.
实际上艾蜜莉周末要来
Uh, in fact Emily's coming into town this weekend.
要不要我们一起吃个饭  周末晚上好吗
why don't you say we all have dinner? Say, Sunday night?
太好了  是吗
That would be great! Yeah?
好吧  那就说定了  好的
All right. It's a date! Yeah.
"撑着点"   你才撑着点
"Hang in there." You hang in there.
你说什么  没有  我在唱歌
Did you say something? No, just singing.
（贝翠丝婚纱广场）
天哪
Oh, my God!
你看这件
Oh, look at this one!
好美  对
It's so beautiful. Yeah. Oof.
她们中有一半最后还会离婚
Yeah, but y'know, about half of these will end up getting divorced.
我能帮忙吗
May I help you ladies?
是的  我来取定好的礼服
Oh, yes, umm, I'm here to pick up a dress that you have on hold
好的  请问什么名字
Yes, what's the name, please?
艾蜜莉华森  有  已经准备好了
Emily Waltham. Oh, yes, I have it right here.
你要试穿吗  华森夫人
Would you like to try it on, Miss Waltham?
好的
Okay.
你是我见过最美的新娘
You're the most beautiful bride I've ever seen.
真的  可不是吗
I am, aren't I?
华森夫人
Miss Waltham?
在  我们要打烊了
Yes? We're closing.
好吧
All right.
请把戒指还给我
And could I get my ring back?
好吧  兄弟  该翻身了
All right, buddy. Time to roll over.
不  不  不  ...
No, no! No, no, no, no, no!
你得去医院了  你要去医院
You are going to a clinic! You're going to a clinic!
还有睡衣店
And a pajama store!
她有用杯子吗
Does she use the cups?
有  我相信她用
Yes, I believe she does.
她用盘子吗  有  我相信她用
Does she use the plates? Yes, I believe she does!
谢谢
Thank you. Heh.
非常谢谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢你能来
Oh, thank you for coming.
等下  不行  让我进去
Uh, just a second. No, no! Let me in!
菲比   对
Phoebe? Yeah?
你能等一小会儿吗  不行
Can you just hold on for one minute? No!
你现在就得让我进去
You have to let me in right now!
你一个人吗   对
Are you alone? Yes!
好吧
All right.
太烦人了
This sucks.
去那诊所检查前  我一晚上都不能睡
I have to stay up all night before I go to the stupid clinic.
困死了
I'm so tired.
现在才六点
It's 6:00.
嗨  嘿
Hi. Hey.
听说你和约书亚   要跟罗斯艾蜜莉一起出去吃饭
I hear you and Joshua are going out with Ross and Emily.
我觉得  这么做很有风度
And I think... I think that's really cool.
是啊  你处理得相当好啊
Yeah, I think you're handling that really well.
"处理"
"Handling it"
什么意思  没什么好处理的
What do you mean? There's nothing to handle.
如果不是和约书亚在交往  也许我接受不了这事
Maybe I would have a problem with this if it wasn't for me and Joshua.
不过反正他们也结不了婚  什么
Y'know, They're not gonna get married anyway. What?
拜托  他们这么草率  简直太可笑了
Come on. They rushed into this thing so fast, it's ridiculous!
他们应该先订婚   一年
They'll be engaged for like what? A year?
这期间  他们俩总会有人想通
And somewhere along the way, one of them is gonna realize what they've done...
然后再取消婚约
...and call the thing off.
你们会先在我的婚礼上跳舞
I'm telling you, you'll be dancing at my wedding before you dance at theirs.
我参加婚礼从不跳舞
You know, I don't dance at weddings.
为什么   婚礼是认识女生的好地方
Why not? Because weddings are a great place to meet women.
而我要跳舞   就像这副德性
When I dance, I look like this.
你好  嘿
Hey, man. Hey.
四周后的今天你们有事吗
So, what are you guys doing four weeks from today?
没事  没事
Nothing. Nothing.
我…
I am...
有空
...free.
太好了  因为艾蜜莉和我一个月后要结婚
Great, Because Emily and I are getting married in a month!
什么  没错
What? Yup.
一个月后   对
In a month? Yeah.
你是说30天后  对
You mean 30 days? Yeah.
从今天算起  对
From now? Yeah.
太棒了  对
That's great! Yeah, ha, ha.
艾蜜莉一直想在她父母结婚的  同一个漂亮地方举行婚礼
Emily always wanted to get married in this beautiful place that her parents got married ...
但那里马上要拆除了  所以
...but it's gonna be torn down, so...
我知道这很疯狂  但所有事从头到尾都很疯狂
I know it's crazy, but everything up 'til now has been so crazy,...
我不知道  就是感觉该这样
...and I don't know, just feels right, you know?
那是我经期的第二天
Hey, that's the day after I start menstruating!
这不是我的
This isn't mine.
嘿  瑞秋
Ahem Hey, Rachel.
嗨
Hi.
什么事
What's up? Oh, heh.
你在电话里的声音神经兮兮的
Your voice sounded all squeaky on the phone.
没事  我就是想见你
Oh, nothing. I just wanted to see you.
见你  抱你
See you and hug you.
见你  真好
Ha, ha. See you, heh.
感觉真好
Great. Yeah!
坐
Sit.
你还好吗
You okay?
好得不得了  我非常  非常地高兴
I'm more than okay. I am really, really happy.
想知道为什么吗
Want to know why?
我想吗
Do I?
因为我真为我们俩高兴
Because I am really happy about us.
我认为我们发展得很好
I think we are, I think we are so on the right track.
我意思是  我们相处的好  我们也很合拍
Y'know? I mean, I think we are working. I think we are clicking.
你懂吗  当然
You know? Yeah, sure, sure.
我们  我们很合拍
We're... We're clicking. Yeah.
如果说有什么小缺憾
If there was just one little area...
需要加强的  我觉得
...where I think we need to work on, I would think...
应该就是我们还不够疯狂
...it's that we're just not crazy enough.
老实说  我不太同意这点
I got to say, I'm not too sure I agree with that.
好吧  你知道吗  你对的
Well, yeah. You know, yeah, you're right.
当然  我们也很开心
I mean, we have our fun. Yeah?
但是
But, uh...
我是说像疯--狂一样  你懂吗
We ju... I mean like craaaazy! You know?
好吧  这个
Okay. All right.
这个听起来  是有点点仓促
This is gonna, this is gonna to sound, you know, a little, um, hasty.
但你先听听看
But, uh, just go with me.
我们结婚怎么样
What if we got married?
什么  我知道  你会觉得
What? Oh, I know. It's so totally like:
"哇  我们行吗"  我是说
"Whoa, can we do this?" You know? I mean...
就是感觉该这样  你不觉得  该这样吗
But it just feels right. Don't you think? It does.
就是感觉应该这样   你说呢
I mean, it just feels right. Don't you...?
瑞秋
Rachel, um...
你是个
you're
很特别
a real
的女性
special lady.
但是我的离婚还没办完
But my divorce isn't final yet
而且  我们才约会了四次
and, and, and we've been on four dates.
所以我是想说  不要
So I'm thinking  no...
不过
but
谢了
thanks.
你这个白痴
You idiot!
（诊所）
姓名  乔伊崔比亚尼
Your name, please? Joey Tribbiani.
你是不是整夜没睡觉  来准备接受诊疗
Mm-hm. and did you stay up all night in preparation for your sleep study.
嗨  先生
Uh, sir?
是的  好的
Yes, he did.
好吧  几分钟后我们再叫你
All right. We'll call you in a few minutes.
哇啊  嘿
Whoa. Hey.
看那个女孩  好惹火
Check out that girl. She is really hot.
是啊
Yeah, she is.
你好吗
How you doing?
怎样   你在跟跟整屋人搭讪
What? You're coming on to the entire room.
我是钱德  我是玛乔莉
I'm Chandler. Hi. I'm Marjorie. Hi.
你介意我坐吗  请便
Do you mind if I sit? No, please.
你来看什么
So, uh, what are you in for?
我说梦话
I talk in my sleep.
真巧啊  我专爱听梦话
What a coincidence. I listen in my sleep.
给个你的电话好吗
So why don't you give me your number?
准备好了吗   好了
Are you ready? Okay. Yeah.
我接到了  我的
I got it! Mine! Aah!
恭喜你  谢谢
Congratulations! Thank you! Ha-ha-ha.
换我  换我  好
Okay, my turn, my turn! Okay!
好了吗
Okay, ready?
好
Okay.
你扔的也太没水准了
That was a terrible throw!
我才不直接扔给你  太假了
I won't throw it right to you. That's not real.
你看我  还担心太假吗
Look at me. My big concern is what's real?
天哪
Oh, my God.
我们真的很悲哀  对吧
We're really sad, aren't we?
是啊  没错
Yeah, I think we are.
这还不是我的婚纱
This isn't even my dress.
至少不是去 "还不算太晚婚纱店" 租的
At least you didn't rent yours from a store called "It's Not Too Late."
我要去换掉  我也是
I'm changing out of this. Me too.
要不  再过半小时后  我也是
In, like, a half an hour? Me too.
这次直接扔给我  好吧
All right, now throw it straight this time. Okay.
我下一个结婚了
I'm getting married next! Yay!
我现在好讨厌一般普通的衣服
I hate my regular clothes now.
低头一看就知道
You know? I look down and I know...
今天不是我人生最特别的日子
...this isn't gonna be the most special day of my life.
是啊  我意思是刚开始还挺好玩
Yeah. I mean, it was kind of fun for a while...
你不觉得有点傻吗
...but didn't you feel kind of silly?
是有点
I guess.
哦  天哪
Oh, my God!
啊  你这个骗子
Oh, you're such a cheater!
哈罗  小可爱们
Hello, little ones.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
乔伊不再打呼了吗  会的
So is Joey going to stop snoring? Yep!
而且有个美女答应跟我约会
And a beautiful woman agreed to go out with me.
乔伊本来也想约她  但她选了我
Joey wanted to ask her out, but, uh, you know, she picked me.
怎么可能呢
How'd that happen?
因为我更酷
Because I'm cooler.
不  说真的
No, seriously.
她是那种  让乔伊意识不清的女孩
She's the kind of girl... Joey was unconscious.
嗨  伙计们  你们好吗
Hey, you guys! What's happening?
天哪
Oh, my God.
那是什么  这是睡眠诊所给的
What is that? Oh! They gave it to me at the sleep clinic.
帮助我不打呼
And it's going to help me not to snore.
那你现在在睡觉吗
Well, are you asleep right now, Joe?
没睡觉应该不用咬着它吧
'Cause I don't think you have to wear it unless you are!
我当然知道
I know I don't have to.
味道不错
It tastes good.
还有  你看起来很酷
Plus, you look cool.
我刚给约书亚打电话
Well, I just called Joshua.
怎么样
Oh, how'd it go?
我尽力说服他我不是
I did my best to convince him that I'm not...
想结婚想的发疯的女孩
...some crazy girl who is dying to get married.
我只是处在情绪低落的非常时期  他怎么说
And I'm going through a hard time. What'd he say?
他的录音电话表示很理解
Well, uh, his answering machine was very understanding.
我好郁闷
I feel blue. Ugh.
啊  甜心
Aw. Sweety.
我打赌他一定会给你电话
I bet you anything he'll call you again.
可能吧  但我想  我都不在乎这个了
Yeah, maybe. But, you know, I don't think I even care.
我想他不是我为之伤心的那个
I don't think he's the one I'm sad about.
我知道我说过  我完全不在意罗斯结婚
I know I said I'm totally okay with Ross getting married.
但是实际上
But as it turns out...
我还接受不了
...I don't think I'm handling it all that well.
是啊  有可能
Yeah, maybe.
我正在努力寻找原因
And I'm just trying to figure out why.
找到了
Any luck?
是啊  罗斯和我总是
Well, yeah. You know how Ross and I have always been...
和了分  分了和  然后又分
...on-again, off-again, on-again, off-again?
我一直觉得总会在什么时候
I guess I just figured, somewhere down the road...
我们又会和好
...we would be on-again.
又会的
Again.
知道吗  我们都这么觉得
You know what? I think we all did.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿
Hey.
我订好了周日晚上的餐厅了
I got us reservations for Sunday night.
9点整厄尼之家餐厅  行吗
How about Ernie's at 9:00?
行  你最好还是改成3
Yeah, well, you, uh, better make it for three.
但下午3点不应该会饿吧
See, I don't know if we're going to be hungry at 3:00.
是 3个人
Three people.
约书亚不会去了
Joshua's not going to be there.
怎么了  我想他是要跟我分手了
What happened? Um, well, I think he broke up with me.
天哪  为什么
No. Why?
很明显  他经不起惊吓
Apparently, he scares easy.
瑞秋  我很难过
Rachel, I'm sorry.
没关系
Eh, it's okay.
有时候  人生往往会事与愿违
Sometimes things don't work out the way you thought they would.
过来
Come here.
你不用去接艾蜜莉吗
Oh, hey, don't you have to go pick up Emily?
要啊
Yeah. Yeah.
你行吗  可以
Are you okay? Yeah.
我还有姐妹们陪我
I got my girls.
好吧
Okay.
你知道怎么才能让你振作起来
Hey, you know what might cheer you up?
什么
What?
说实话
I got to tell you...
我的心情真的好多了
...this really does put me in a better mood.
真希望有整天穿婚纱的工作
Ah, I wish there was a job where I could wear this all the time.
也许以后真会有的
Maybe someday there will be.
完了  是钱德来借晚上约会的蜡烛
Oh, God, that's Chandler coming by to borrow candles for his big date.
瑞秋  别开门  他会看见我们
No, Rachel, don't get it! He'll see us!
对   新郎不能见新娘
No, yeah! The groom cannot see the bride.
我又不嫁给钱德
I'm not going to marry Chandler.
被他看到就得嫁了
Not after this!
伙计们  放轻松就对了
Okay guys, just relax.
我愿意
I do!
我得走了  等等  约书亚
I gotta go. Wait, Joshua!
这次真的是玩完了
Yeah, well, that ought to do it.
这里有吃的   够了
Food's here. Fair enough.
还有15分钟
Fifteen-minute warning.
太迟了
Late.
大哥  我还想睡觉呢
Dude, I am trying to sleep!